Guide to the Hasia Diner Papers ca. 1970-1992 MC 153
New York University Archives
Hasia Diner Papers
Bulk, 1970-1992
1960-1992
MC 153
New York University Archives
12.0 linear feet 12 linear feet (12 boxes)
Hasia Diner is a Professor of American Jewish History and is also the Director of the Goldstein-Goren Center for American Jewish History at NYU. Her research interests include American Jewish history, American immigration history and women's history. The following collection includes her research notes for four of her manuscripts.
Diner, Hasia R.
Arrangement
Folders contain notes and source material arranged by the author.
The files are grouped into one series
I, Research Notes
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains 12 linear feet of undated research notes.
Boxes 1-3 contain research materials for Erin's Daughters, boxes 4-6 contain research notes for In the Almost Promised Land, boxes 7-8 contain research notes for Jewish Self-Governance and boxes 9-12 contain research notes for A Time for Gathering.
Historical/Biographical Note
Hasia R. Diner is the Paul and Sylvia Steinberg Professor of American Jewish History at New York University, with a joint appointment in the departments of history and the Skirball Department of Hebrew and Judaic Studies and is the Director of the Goldstein Goren Center for American Jewish History. Previously she was a professor in the Department of American Studies at the University of Maryland at College Park. Professor Diner held a Fulbright Professorship at the University of Haifa in Israel, 1990-1991. She has been a Lilly Fellow at the Mary I. Bunting Institute at Radcliffe College, in 1998 won election to membership in American Academy of Jewish Research and in 2004 to the Society of American Historians. She has also been a fellow at the Shelby Cullom Davis Center for Historical Research at Princeton University. She received her Ph.D. in History at the University of Illinois-Chicago. Her bachelor's degree was awarded in 1968 from the University of Wisconsin and her master's at the University of Chicago in 1970.
She has published many books and articles, including In the Almost Promised Land: American Jews and Blacks, 1915-1935 (1977, 1995), A Time For Gathering. 1820-1880: The Second Migration (1992), and Erin's Daughters in America: Irish Immigrant Women in the Nineteenth Century (1984).
Sources:
Hasia Diner, research notes.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection. Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted. Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
This collection is in
off-site storage
.
Provenance
These records were transferred to the University Archives by Hasia Diner in 1998.
Diner, Hasia R.; New York University.; African Americans |x Relations with Jews.; Immigrants |z United States; Irish American women |x History |y 19th century.; Jews |z United States |x History |y 19th century.; Jews |z United States |x History.; Jews |z United States |x Social conditions.; Jews, German |z United States |x History |y 19th century.; Judaism |Z United States |x History |y 19th century.; Judaism |z United States |x History.; Notes.; Reference sources.; Research (document genres).; Sephardim |z United States |x History.; United States |x Ethnic relations.; United States |z Emigration and immigration.
- Series I: Research Notes
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Education, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    bar code: 3 1142 04225439 4
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Famine, undated, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Ireland, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Labor, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Male-female relations, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Migration, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Women's Roles, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225440 2
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Employment, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Family in Ireland, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Ireland, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Irish women's support groups, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Trade unions, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Women and employment, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Chapter 6, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225441 0
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Chapter 6, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Family, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Services for Irish, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Services for women, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes: Women's social life, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Erin's Daughters research notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes: Causes, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225442 8
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes: Chapter 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes: Chapter 3, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes: Final chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research note, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes: Labor, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225443 6
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes: Music, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes: Sermons, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes: Chapter 1, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225444 4
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes: Chapter 2, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - In the Almost Promised Land research notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225445 1
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225446 9
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Self Governance notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Notes on German Situation, 1960-1995 (Box 8)
  - Notes, 1960-1995 (Box 8)
  - Kaplan, 1960-1995 (Box 8)
  - Introduction and Chapter One, 1960-1995 (Box 8)
  - Footnotes, 1960-1995 (Box 8)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225447 7
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225448 5
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225449 3
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Time For Gathering notes: photos, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 04225450 1
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Time For Gathering notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)